<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-10T13:24:42+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chela</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">زندگی بین دو قطب امید و نا امیدی-انتخاب ما امید است</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/anniversary-farsi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="زندگی بین دو قطب امید و نا امیدی-انتخاب ما امید است" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/anniversary-farsi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/anniversary-farsi.html">&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;
این پیامی است برای تمام دختران افغان، از طرف شاگردان &quot;چله&quot;. امروز چهار سال شد که ما در این کابوس زندگی می کنیم. دروازه های مکتب که روزی ما را به دنیایی از رویاها و آرزوهایمان وصل می کرد، حالا به روی ما بسته شده، به دلیل دختر بودن ما ازرفتن به مکتب محروم شدیم. ما نمیتوانیم درس بخوانیم و کار کنیم. بعضی از ما تن به ازدواج اجباری دادیم. عده ای هم با خشونت های خانوادگی روبه رو هستیم. بیرون رفتن از خانه همیشه با ترس از اینکه مبادا توسط طالبان دستگیر شویم همراه است. حتی یک اصطلاح جدید به وجود آمده – &quot; دختر خانه&quot;. این نشان دهنده این است که نقش زنان به عقب رانده شده و ما در زندگی اجتماعی نامرِئی شده ایم و صدای ما شنیده نمی شود. بعضی از ما این درد را تحمل نتوانستیم و دوستان مان را به دلیل نا امیدی از دست داده ایم.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;

اما امروز، ما یک پیام برای همه شما داریم. این پیام ساده است – امید را انتخاب کنید. همانطور که ویکتور فرانکل می گوید: &quot; آخرین آزادی انسان این است که در هر شرایطی که قرار داشته باشد طرز فکر و راه  خود را انتخاب کند.&quot;  شما میان نا امیدی و امید حق انتخاب دارید و باید امید را انتخاب کنید. ما این کار را انجام دادیم. ما گروهی از دختران افغان هستیم که ثابت می کنیم شما هم می توانید.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;

از تجربه خود می توانیم به شما بگوییم: نا امیدی سخت و دردناک است، اما امید - گرچه سخت تر- آرام بخش است. اول باید به خودمان تکیه کنیم. روی مراقبت از خود، رشد فردی و تحصیلات خویش متمرکز باشیم. ناجی شما همان کسی است که در آینه می بینید. اما این را نباید فراموش کنیم که همه کار ها را نمی توانیم به تنهایی انجام بدهیم، و نباید تنها باشیم. راه های پیدا کنید، هرچند که کوچک باشد، تا بتوانید با دیگر زنان و دختران در ارتباط باشید. اگر دسترسی به انترنیت دارید می توانید به اجتماع و گروهای آنلاین چه در داخل کشور و چه در خارج از کشور وصل شوید. کسانی هستند که به شما فکر می کنند، آنچه جریان دارد را میبینند، به شما باور دارند و می خواهند کمک کنند. ما در صنف های آنلاین اشتراک کردیم و با افرادی در سراسر دنیا آشنا شدیم که وقت و دآنش خود را برای آموزش رایگان به دختران افغان وقف کردند. آن ها فقط معلم نبودند – انسان های با قلب مهربان و با احساس بودند که با عشق و فداکاری به ما آموزش دادند. حمایت آنها می تواند زندگی شما را تغییر دهد.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;

چیزهای که با ما کمک کردن شامل این ها می شود: مطالعه روانشناسی، تمرین یوگا و ورزش منظم، کتاب خواندن و نوشتن ، یادگیری زبان های جدید ، و پیوستن به جامعه ای که ما را حمایت می کند، یادگرفتن اینکه چطور در موقع فشار آرامش خود را حفظ کنیم ، احساسات خود را کنترل کنیم، و با خودمان مهربان باشیم و باور داشته باشیم که رشد حتی در زمان بحران هم ممکن است. بالاتر از همه چیز – ما منبع امید برای یکدیگر هستیم. چیزی که الهام بخش ما است و به ما امید می دهد، دیدن دختران جوان افغان است که با وجود واقیعت تلخی که با آن رو به رو هستند، همچنان برای رویاهای شان به جنگیدن ادامه می دهد.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;

پس حالا از خودتان بپرسید – آیا شما عضو یک جامعه هستید؟ به کدام جامعه می توانید بپیوندید؟ کدام جامعه را می توانید به وجود بیاورید؟ آیا به انترنیت دسترسی دارید؟ آیا قادر هستید انگلسی صحبت کنید، حتی یک کم ؟ آیا دختران دیگر را در همسایگی خود می شناسید و راهی برای ملاقات با آنها وجود دارد؟  اگر تنها هستید حالا زمان آن است که دست به کار شوید.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;

ما باور داریم این بی عدالتی، و این تاریکی، موقتی است. باور داریم که روزی صدای دختران افغان آن قدر با قدرت بلند خواهد رفت که این ظلم پایان خواهد یافت. ما باور داریم که پشت هر تاریکی و سختی نور و پاداش بزرگی نهفته است. ما انتخاب کردیم که بجنگیم. ما این روز ها را به یاد خواهیم داشت و یک روز این داستان را به نسل های اینده  خود خواهیم گفت. به آن ها خواهیم گفت – بیبینید ما چی چیزی را تحمل کردیم. برای شان خواهیم گفت چطور توانستیم و موفق شدیم. و به آنها خواهیم گفت که اگر ما توانستیم از این شرایط موفقانه عبور کنیم، تصور کنید که آنها در زندگی به چی چیزهای  که خواهد رسید.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;

ادامه بدهید و به پیش بروید زنان و دختران عزیز افغان. ما می توانیم. امید را انتخاب کنید.
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">این پیامی است برای تمام دختران افغان، از طرف شاگردان &quot;چله&quot;. امروز چهار سال شد که ما در این کابوس زندگی می کنیم. دروازه های مکتب که روزی ما را به دنیایی از رویاها و آرزوهایمان وصل می کرد، حالا به روی ما بسته شده، به دلیل دختر بودن ما ازرفتن به مکتب محروم شدیم. ما نمیتوانیم درس بخوانیم و کار کنیم. بعضی از ما تن به ازدواج اجباری دادیم. عده ای هم با خشونت های خانوادگی روبه رو هستیم. بیرون رفتن از خانه همیشه با ترس از اینکه مبادا توسط طالبان دستگیر شویم همراه است. حتی یک اصطلاح جدید به وجود آمده – &quot; دختر خانه&quot;. این نشان دهنده این است که نقش زنان به عقب رانده شده و ما در زندگی اجتماعی نامرِئی شده ایم و صدای ما شنیده نمی شود. بعضی از ما این درد را تحمل نتوانستیم و دوستان مان را به دلیل نا امیدی از دست داده ایم.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Living between the poles of despair and hope - we choose hope</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/anniversary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Living between the poles of despair and hope - we choose hope" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/anniversary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/anniversary.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a message to all the girls in Afghanistan, from the students of Chela. Today marks four years that we have been living in this nightmare. The school gates that once welcomed us to a world of dreams and ambitions now stand locked, shutting us out only because we are girls. We cannot study or work. Some of us are forced to marry. Some of us face domestic violence. Stepping outside our homes brings with it the constant fear of being taken away by the Taliban. There is even a new term — “housegirl”. It reflects how women’s roles have been pushed backward, leaving us invisible and unheard in public life. Some of us cannot bear this pain and we have lost our friends to despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But today, we have a message for you all. The message is simple – choose hope. As Victor Frankl says “The last of the human freedoms: to choose one’s attitude in any given set of circumstances, to choose one’s own way.” You have a choice between despair and hope. You must choose hope. We did. We are a group of girls that are living proof that you can do it. Here’s how we did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our experience, we can tell you this: despair is harsh and painful, but hope—though even harder—is comforting. We must rely, firstly, on ourselves. Focus on self-care, personal growth and education. Your savior lives in the mirror. But we must also remember we cannot do everything alone, and we do not have to be alone. Find ways, however small, to connect with other women and girls. If you have access to the internet, you can find access to an online community, inside and outside Afghanistan. There are people that care about you, see what you are going through, that believe in you and want to help. We have joined online classes, and met people from all over the world who volunteered their time and knowledge to teach Afghan girls for free. These were not just teachers—they were kind-hearted, passionate human beings who taught us with love and dedication. Their support can change your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things we found that helped include studying psychology, practicing yoga and exercising regularly, learning how to stay calm under pressure, and how to control our emotions, being kind to ourselves and believing that growth is possible, even in times of crisis, reading books, learn new languages, writing, and joining a supportive community. Above all – we are the source of hope for one another. What inspires us and gives us hope is seeing young Afghan girls, despite the harsh reality they face, continue to fight for their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself now – are you part of a community? What community can you join? What community could you start? Do you have access to the internet? Can you speak English, even a little bit? Do you know other girls in your neighbourhood, and is there anyway to meet with them? If you are alone, now is the time to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe this injustice, this darkness, is temporary. We believe one day the voices of Afghan girls will rise so powerfully that this oppression will end. We believe that behind every darkness there is light. We believe that behind every hardship lies a great reward. We choose to fight. We will remember these days and one day we will tell the stories to the next generation. We will tell them – look what we endured. We will tell them how we did it. And we will tell them that if we could overcome this, imagine what they can achieve in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping going dear Afghan women and girls. We can do it. Choose hope.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a message to all the girls in Afghanistan, from the students of Chela. Today marks four years that we have been living in this nightmare. The school gates that once welcomed us to a world of dreams and ambitions now stand locked, shutting us out only because we are girls. We cannot study or work. Some of us are forced to marry. Some of us face domestic violence. Stepping outside our homes brings with it the constant fear of being taken away by the Taliban. There is even a new term — “housegirl”. It reflects how women’s roles have been pushed backward, leaving us invisible and unheard in public life. Some of us cannot bear this pain and we have lost our friends to despair.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The silent desires of an Afghan girl</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/12/silent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The silent desires of an Afghan girl" /><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/12/silent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/12/silent.html">&lt;p&gt;Certainly, here is a story that touches on the struggles of girls who due to conflict and
oppressive regimes are unable to go to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She lives in a small, quiet town in Afghanistan nestled among the towering mountains. She was a bright and hopeful 12-years-old girl, with dreams that stretched far beyond the narrow streets of her village. Like many children, she loved learning. She would often read the few books she had, her imagination traveling far beyond the hills, taking her to places she could only dream of. Her favorite subject was science and she dreamed of becoming a doctor, helping the sick and bringing hope to those in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all of that changed when Taliban returned to power in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Taliban’s resurgence, she had been attending school with her friends enjoying the sense of freedom that education gave her. She loved the days when she could rush to school, eager to learn new things, to sit wait their classmates and share stories of their lives. School was her safe place, her escape from the hardships of life in her village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as the Taliban tightened their control over the country, everything that once felt normal and hopeful to her became uncertain. One morning, the school’s in her town were suddenly closed. The government issued an announcement: girls could no longer attend school past the sixth grade. She could not understand why. Why were they being told they couldn’t go to school anymore? Why was her dream of becoming a doctor slipping away from her hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days turned into weeks, and the streets of her town grew quiet. The laughter of children was replaced by the sound of silence, as girls her age were forced to stay at home, confined within the walls of their houses. She and her friend no longer gathered after school to talk about their lessons or dreams. Instead, they sat in their rooms, staring out the window, hoping for a change that seemed impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her father, once a teacher himself, tried to comfort her, though his heart was heavy with sorrow. He understood how much education meant to her and how much it had shaped her. He would occasionally teach her in secret, whispering lessons into the quiet corners of their home but he feared that of they were caught, the consequences would be severe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am so sorry, my daughter” he would say, his filled with helplessness “I wish things were different”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she never stopped dreaming. Each day, she would take out her notebook and continue writing down the lessons she had learned in the past. She studied the world through books she managed to find, hoping one day to be able to return to a classroom. Her mother, a quiet but strong woman, tried to keep her spirit alive. She would tell her stories of women who fought for their education, who overcame oppression and hardship. But even her stories though powerful, could not mask the deep sadness in her eyes. She could not help but feel that the world was passing her by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, she overhead a conversation between her father and her older brother. Her father spoke of the new restrictions of how many girls in the country were now locked inside their homes with no future in sight. We may not even have the chance to leave this country, to give them a better life” he said, his voice breaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her heart sank. The thought of being trapped in a life without the chance to fulfill her dreams was unbearable. She knew that many girls across the country were facing the same fate. They were no longer allowed to go to school. As months passed, the reality set in for her. She was growing up in a world where girls were being denied their most basic rights. The right to learn. Her dreams of becoming a doctor, of helping others seems increasingly out of reach. But she did not give up. She continued to write, continued to study and in the quiet moments when no one is watching, she would close her eyes and imagine with life would be like if she could return to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She, like many girls around the world had her dreams stolen by forces beyond her control. Yet even in her silence, her hope remained a flicker of light in a dark time. She held on to the belief that one day when the would changed, when things would get better. She would go to school again. And maybe, just maybe, she would one day become the doctor she always wanted to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story represents the harsh reality faced by many girls in Afghanistan and other parts of the world where access to education is denied due to oppressive regimes, war, or cultural restrictions. The pain of these girls like her is not just about missing school, it is about missing out on opportunities, dreams and a future that they deserve to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by an Afghan girl&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Certainly, here is a story that touches on the struggles of girls who due to conflict and oppressive regimes are unable to go to school.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who cannot go to school</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who cannot go to school" /><published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/school.html">&lt;p&gt;As we know, before the Taliban, we had a simple life. Everyone was busy with their own lifestyle—teachers, students, tailors, beauticians, and everyone else. All of us could do things for ourselves: earning money, getting an education, working, and so on. But now, it’s gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then, if someone got married, hotels weren’t expensive, and nobody charged extra just to make more money for themselves. But now, everything has changed. They’ve taken our country, our freedom, our education—we’ve lost ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never a silent girl. At that time, I was busy with my lessons, waking up early every morning. Life was so fantastic for me. Staying at home now makes me feel bored. All my goals were so clear back then, but now, it feels like they’ve all been erased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they came to our province, I was in the middle of my school exams. It was my final exam to finish 12th grade. Our teacher gave us three exams in one day, even though I had only prepared for one subject. Then we reached the Kankor exam, which is a big exam that determines our future. In the exam, we weren’t allowed to choose other provinces—only neighboring ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed that exam and was accepted in my province. If I had been able to continue my studies, I would have finished by now, and I might even have a job. But they closed everything and said it would only be temporary. As we can see, it’s still closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they said all women should wear masks, and we accepted that too. But some days ago, they started abducting girls because of their hijabs, and they even beat them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After they came to our country, in all universities and schools, boys and girls used to study together like siblings. But everything changed. Last winter, I went to my English course, and the Taliban came to our class. They asked our teacher, “Who allowed you to open this course again, and for what purpose?” My teacher replied, “Your boss.” But they said, “No, it’s wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were afraid. They spoke with my teacher for a while and then said, “Start your teaching.” We started again, but they took photos of us and themselves. After that day, one of them, who was outside the class, recorded a video of the other girls and sent it to their office. As a result, they closed the course again. It is still closed, and we continue to experience very bad days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite everything, I want to stay strong. No one can determine my future except me. My future is in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As we know, before the Taliban, we had a simple life. Everyone was busy with their own lifestyle—teachers, students, tailors, beauticians, and everyone else. All of us could do things for ourselves: earning money, getting an education, working, and so on. But now, it’s gone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl confronted by the Taliban in Bamyan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/bitterness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl confronted by the Taliban in Bamyan" /><published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/bitterness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/bitterness.html">&lt;p&gt;The story I want to write is difficult for me, as it reflects the story of my life—a girl born in one of the worst times and under unfair conditions, a life full of bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bitterness stems from the fact that I had no influence or fault in choosing my circumstances, yet I am judged—harshly and unfairly—through the lens of gender and ethnicity. As a girl, I should have the most basic rights in life, but, unfortunately, I am denied even those. This harsh reality is so bitter and tragic for me that I drown in thought for hours. The bitterness of my story—and the stories of millions of other girls in every corner of this land—has grown even more bitter under the Taliban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was little, I heard the name “Taliban” on my father’s radio, which was always tuned to the BBC. The reporter always spoke about them with urgency. I didn’t understand what was being said, but I could tell from my father’s fixed gaze on the radio and his unbroken silence that it was nothing good. To me, the name “Taliban” held no meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me and my friends in that small village, our teammates and toys were more important than anything else. I never understood the truth about the Taliban because that truth was full of humiliation, stoning, executions, whipping, and forcing women and girls into the darkness of their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew older, like the suffering of the people around me, I came to realize that life was more than just toys. But I wish I hadn’t grown up. I wish I could have kept those toys, those happy friends, and the freedom to laugh out loud without judgment or wear what I wanted without fear of a veil. I learned, however, that life does not always follow human wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-15th-of-august&quot;&gt;The 15th of August&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 15th of August marked the beginning of a new era in the history of Afghanistan—a dark and regressive era in a history already full of twists and turns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this period, all the values and achievements we had struggled for—including women’s and girls’ rights, especially the right to education and work—were transformed into suffering. These rights had been gained through immense effort, challenges, and sacrifices. Terrorist attacks, targeted explosions in schools, mosques, and educational centers—particularly against the Hazara community—had plagued us, but we persevered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2021, I began working as a field vaccinator for COVID-19 in Bamyan province, one of the safest yet most deprived provinces over the past 26 years. It was a great opportunity to serve underprivileged people. However, it wasn’t long before we heard the sound of Taliban boots in the city. The tragic story of August 15th began, and everything changed overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our task was clear: My team of three—my coworker Sima, our driver, and I—was scheduled to visit the village of Qoli Haydar. On the way, we were surrounded by ten armed men on motorcycles, carrying white flags. They blocked our car, and fear gripped us as we shouted, “Why are the Taliban here?” I begged the driver, “Please don’t stop the car, just keep moving.” But the men surrounded us and demanded to know: “Where are you going? Who are you? What is your relationship with these girls?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driver, trembling with fear, answered, “They are COVID-19 vaccinators. We’re headed to Qoli Haydar village.” One of the men ordered, “Get out of the car!” The driver complied, while Sima and I remained inside. They ransacked the vehicle, taking everything, including the vaccine carrier and ice packs. One of them, puzzled by the ice packs, asked, “What are these?” The driver explained, “It’s frozen water for keeping the vaccines cold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the Taliban opened an ice pack, drank the water, and remarked, “Wow, cold water!” He shared it with the others, laughing, “Look at them, traveling with such luxuries as cold water.” I whispered to Sima, “If they drink the ice packs, the vaccines will be destroyed.” She begged me to stay silent, but I couldn’t. I stepped out and said in a hoarse voice, “This water is not drinkable; it’s for keeping the vaccines cold.” The men laughed loudly, mocking, “You eat or drink whatever you find!” and threw the ice packs to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another man sneered, “Shameless girls! How dare you work with men without a mahram? Thank God your corrupt government has fallen!” Panic boiled inside me, and dark thoughts swirled in my mind. I looked around, but there was nothing but the burning sun, towering mountains, and trees. Suddenly, one of them called the others away, saying, “Let’s go conquer the district. We’ll deal with these sparrows later.” They sped off on their motorcycles, and we breathed a sigh of relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hurriedly packed our things, got back in the car, and made our way to Qoli Haydar village. When we arrived, all the villagers had gathered in front of the mosque, their faces filled with fear and worry. After introducing ourselves, the village elder informed us, “The government has fallen. The Taliban have overtaken Kabul.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immediately said, “We should return to Jawqol because there’s no mobile network here, and I’m worried about my family in Kabul. I might never see them again.” But the villagers warned us, “The roads are too dangerous now; the Taliban may still be nearby.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite our fears, we managed to vaccinate 45 men and women. As time passed, my anxiety grew. I insisted, “We have to get back to Jawqol. My family will be worried about me.” When we finally reached the clinic, we discovered that all the employees had fled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father called me, and I told him, “I’m coming to Kabul.” But he replied, “Stay where you are. Don’t worry about us. The roads are too dangerous. When the situation improves, I’ll come to you.” Sima returned to her home, and I was left alone in the village. It was incredibly stressful—being a young woman without a mahram in an unfamiliar place. Yet, it was also an opportunity to connect with the women, girls, and people of the village on a deeper level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day, I struggled to comprehend the situation and repeatedly asked myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did the government go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did the commandos go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are the NATO forces and the United Nations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How was it possible for a group of men to emerge from the mountains and deserts and ruin the fate of millions in the blink of an eye? Unfortunately, there was no government, no men’s government, no United Nations, no human rights—only a dirty game in which everyone pursued their own interests. Women and girls were the primary victims of this political power play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the Taliban shattered my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The story I want to write is difficult for me, as it reflects the story of my life—a girl born in one of the worst times and under unfair conditions, a life full of bitterness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who refuses to hate her gender</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/23/gender.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who refuses to hate her gender" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/23/gender</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/23/gender.html">&lt;p&gt;I am a girl living in Afghanistan, having completed my bachelor’s degree in a society where women are often silenced, objectified, and forced to live with limitations. I’ve spent countless moments reflecting on the struggles we face, and the pain of it all has broken me at times. In my culture, especially in Asian countries like mine, when a man touches a woman’s body without consent, it’s not seen as shameful for him. But when she protests, she’s shamed. This injustice is a deep reflection of how little respect society has for a woman’s dignity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up, girls are told their only purpose is to marry, have children, and care for the family, while boys are encouraged to dream—to become leaders, scientists, businessmen. Women’s achievements are rarely celebrated. Where are the Afghan businesswomen, the scientists, the women who have succeeded on their own? Even globally, only a handful of women, like Marie Curie, have earned the Nobel Prize for their groundbreaking work. Why is that? Women have untapped potential, but society binds us with its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a time, during the oppressive Taliban era, when I questioned my worth as a woman. I hated my gender. I asked myself: Why must we bear so much pain—from excruciating periods to the struggles of childbirth and raising children? Even after giving birth, a woman can be blamed if she doesn’t produce a boy. The pain was overwhelming, and I started to lose faith. I wondered why there were no female messengers in religion and why men seemed to dominate history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then after joining education opportunity, I saw a new side of the world—a world full of kind, compassionate people. This shift in perspective changed my life. It made me realize that our worth isn’t tied to our pain or the constraints society places on us. We are defined by our strength, our resilience, and our ability to rise from the challenges we face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to think differently about God’s wisdom. If I could understand everything He has done, if I could think like Him, what would be the difference between us? Would I not be like God if I understood His every choice? Women are not accidents or lesser beings. We are strong, powerful creations with a purpose, and it is this strength that will shape the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all the women reading this: You are not alone. Your worth is immeasurable. No matter the struggles, your strength and courage define you. Know this—you are so much more than what society tries to make you believe. God created you strong, and it is in this strength that we find hope for a better world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am a girl living in Afghanistan, having completed my bachelor’s degree in a society where women are often silenced, objectified, and forced to live with limitations. I’ve spent countless moments reflecting on the struggles we face, and the pain of it all has broken me at times. In my culture, especially in Asian countries like mine, when a man touches a woman’s body without consent, it’s not seen as shameful for him. But when she protests, she’s shamed. This injustice is a deep reflection of how little respect society has for a woman’s dignity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl with a broken dream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/22/dreams.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl with a broken dream" /><published>2025-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/22/dreams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/22/dreams.html">&lt;p&gt;In the heart of darkness, when everything falls into silence, only the sound of silent dreams echoes in our ears. These dreams live in the heart of an Afghan girl; a girl who holds dreams and hopes in her heart. But in the real world, amidst the ruins of war and oppression, her dreams die one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an Afghan girl. A girl who sat in the classroom during the day and slept all night with big dreams. I wished to be useful to my country one day through my education. In my world, education was the only asylum for me. But the Taliban came and changed everything. I remember that one day in Seyed al-Shahda, there was an explosion and thousands of girls became martyrs. That day, it wasn’t only those girls who became martyrs; the souls of thousands of other girls were buried with them.Our house was near that school. I witnessed how  parents and families were broken, and how they died because of their pain. I also cried for them, for my country, for thousands of girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, when I went to school, I saw a blood-stained bag near to the mosque. I couldn’t control myself and cried. As I walked the half-hour distance to school, I kept crying. Perhaps thousands of other girls were being destroyed too. That day, the entire class was hopeless and upset. No one wanted  to study. I will never forget when our English teacher came in, greeted us, and then started teaching. But no one was wanted to study or even answer. When our teacher asked why, everyone said, “Why should we study? In the end, our fate will be the same as theirs. We will die too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But our teacher said something I have never forgotten. He said, “You should study for yourselves, and go abroad through scholarships or any other way. Don’t stay here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that moment, the only thing I thought about was my country and my people. I told the teacher, “If you and I are supposed to run away, then who will build this country? Who will serve it?” I responded. “You don’t want to go?” he asked me in disbelief. “No, why should I leave?” I replied seriously. If a million dollars is offered to you, would you still not leave?” He asked me again. But I stood with what I’ve said before “No.” This is my final answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gave me a puzzled look ,after awhile, he replied “You say this now, but one day, you will wish to leave. “Never!” I stated with certainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how wrong I was. I was a girl who never wanted to leave. Because I was not afraid of death, but I  was afraid of the destruction of my dreams. And that day, I said those words because I wanted to prove myself through knowledge and education and achieve my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a girl whose entire life and everything, even my belongings, was only knowledge. It was the only thing that was important  to me. I was so serious about my studying and school that I had even distanced myself from my childhood world. The day I first entered school, it took me years to realize that my father had passed away. Before that, I didn’t know and thought he was in Iran. But two days later, when I had just entered school, I found out that my father had died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a girl who had wished for seven or eight years to see her father just once, this news was harder than anything else. Some nights, I cried under the blanket, but I promised myself that one day, I would make my father proud. My father had brought us from the village to the city for education, and I promised that through education, I would make him proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Taliban took over Kabul, I was studying a history book. When I heard that the Taliban had taken the city, I closed the history book and said to myself, “finish.” And it truly finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, my mother became ill, and I went from being a girl who saw her  life in education to a girl who was only a nurse and caregiver for her mother. The situation had changed so much that I couldn’t even get close to my books. When my mother recovered and I returned to my books, everything had changed. Not only the situation, but I had changed as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taliban killed my dreams with their actions.Now, the only thing I want is to leave this country. See what the Taliban have done to this girl. What have they done to a girl who once had no desire to leave? My dreams and goals were all tied to this country and its government, but the Taliban took them from me by closing the doors of knowledge. Even if I go to the best country and study the best fields, I will never be the same girl again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dream was to study at Kabul University. To walk through the streets of Kabul and find a job. My dream was the happiness of my people and their smiles. But these dreams are dead. They were buried under the banner of the Taliban. Even if I leave one day, I will still not be the same girl. In reality, the Taliban killed a girl whose homeland was her life. They killed everything within me that was called “patriotism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I ask myself: “Where have I gone? What part of my life am I in now?” I was the girl whose everything was her country. Now, how can she leave it? Even if years pass, I will never find myself. The Taliban killed dreams that could have been realized in any country, except in their own. Even if I achieve my goals, my dreams are dead. Because in this country, no dream is fulfilled. This is the truth of the death of dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can no longer live as I once did. The Taliban, in fact, not only killed our bodies, but our souls and dreams as well. This pain is harder than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I still wonder if there will ever be a day when I can rebuild this country? Maybe not. Maybe I will just have to live with the memory of my dreams and remain loyal to them in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In the heart of darkness, when everything falls into silence, only the sound of silent dreams echoes in our ears. These dreams live in the heart of an Afghan girl; a girl who holds dreams and hopes in her heart. But in the real world, amidst the ruins of war and oppression, her dreams die one by one. I’m an Afghan girl. A girl who sat in the classroom during the day and slept all night with big dreams. I wished to be useful to my country one day through my education. In my world, education was the only asylum for me. But the Taliban came and changed everything. I remember that one day in Seyed al-Shahda, there was an explosion and thousands of girls became martyrs. That day, it wasn’t only those girls who became martyrs; the souls of thousands of other girls were buried with them.Our house was near that school. I witnessed how parents and families were broken, and how they died because of their pain. I also cried for them, for my country, for thousands of girls. The next morning, when I went to school, I saw a blood-stained bag near to the mosque. I couldn’t control myself and cried. As I walked the half-hour distance to school, I kept crying. Perhaps thousands of other girls were being destroyed too. That day, the entire class was hopeless and upset. No one wanted to study. I will never forget when our English teacher came in, greeted us, and then started teaching. But no one was wanted to study or even answer. When our teacher asked why, everyone said, “Why should we study? In the end, our fate will be the same as theirs. We will die too.” But our teacher said something I have never forgotten. He said, “You should study for yourselves, and go abroad through scholarships or any other way. Don’t stay here.” In that moment, the only thing I thought about was my country and my people. I told the teacher, “If you and I are supposed to run away, then who will build this country? Who will serve it?” I responded. “You don’t want to go?” he asked me in disbelief. “No, why should I leave?” I replied seriously. If a million dollars is offered to you, would you still not leave?” He asked me again. But I stood with what I’ve said before “No.” This is my final answer. He gave me a puzzled look ,after awhile, he replied “You say this now, but one day, you will wish to leave. “Never!” I stated with certainty.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who is a symbol for change</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/21/symbol.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who is a symbol for change" /><published>2025-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/21/symbol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/21/symbol.html">&lt;p&gt;The Courage of……..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A girl lived in a small village in Northern Afghanistan, surrounded by rugged hills and vast stretches of farmland. Her family was not wealthy, but they lived comfortably with enough food to eat and a small cozy home. She had always been a curious and bright child. She loved books and learning, often reading stories under the shade of a pomegranate tree near her house. But in her village, girls didn’t go to school. Education was considered unnecessary for girls, especially when there were other tasks to be done, like fetching water, cooking and helping with the farm. Her parents loved her deeply and wanted the best for her. But like many others in the village they believed that girls should prepared for marriage and family life, not education. However, her spirit could not be contained. She had big dreams that she wasn’t ready to give up on. Every time her younger brother went of to school her heart ached. She would watch him walk with his schoolbag, his face filled with excitement for the lessons ahead.  She would ask him about what he learned when he returned, and he would patiently tell her everything, even though she wasn’t able to attend school herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, after hearing another story about how a girl from a nearby village had become a teacher. She made a decision. She would learn, even if it meant breaking the rules of her village. She started by sneaking into her brother’s school in the afternoons, sitting quietly at the back of the classroom. Her brother didn’t know and neither did the teacher, but her thirst for knowledge grew every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first it was difficult. She was shy and nervous, worried about being discovered, but she had a fire inside her that kept her going. She learned how to read and write, starting with the letters of alphabet, then small words, and eventually reading entire stories. The teacher noticed her presence and rather than scolding her, he secretly encouraged her, giving her extra lessons in private after school. He admired her dedication, knowing that girls in the village were rarely given the chance to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One afternoon, her secret was discovered. Her parents were furious when they found out.  She had been attending school in secret. They didn’t understand why she would risk so much for something they thought was unnecessary. Her father, especially was upset.  “This is not our way” he said. “Girls belong at home not in school. You should be helping your mother, not wasting time with these books.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she didn’t give up. She stood firm and spoke from her heart. “Father, I want to learn because I want to help others. If I can learn, I can be a teacher. I can teach other girls like me who aren’t allowed to go to school. I want to make our village better to help people in a way no one else can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her words struck a chord with her mother, who, though hesitant, quietly supported her. After much discussion, her father, though reluctant, finally agreed to let her continue her studies. The condition was that she would attend school only during the evening hours, after the household chores were done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She worked hard, balancing her studies with the responsibilities at home. Over time, her dedication began to pay off. She became not just a student but a role model for other girls in the village. Slowly, the community began to see the value of education for girls, especially when the witnessed how her knowledge was making a real difference in their lives. She helped her neighbors learn how to read, write and manage the finances better. She shared health and hygiene lessons, and gradually, her efforts started to change the mindset of her village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year passed and she became the first girl in her village to attend high school. Eventually, she became a teacher, teaching not only in her own village but in surrounding communities as well.  Her students were both boys and girls, and she always made sure to encourage the girls in her classes to dream big and pursue education no matter the obstacles.  Her journey wasn’t easy but her perseverance, courage and belief in the power of education helped transform the lives of many. She became a symbol for change, not just in her village but in the broader region, inspiring many young girls to fight for their right to learn, to grow, and to live a life beyond the confines of traditional expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story represents the power of education and the courage to challenge societal norms. It highlights the importance of believing of one’s dreams and fighting for them even when faced with opposition. Like many young girls in Afghanistan and around the world, her determination can inspire others to pursue their goals despite the challenges they may face.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Courage of……..</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who is a warrior</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/12/warrior.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who is a warrior" /><published>2025-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/12/warrior</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/12/warrior.html">&lt;p&gt;At that time, every channel was broadcasting news about the war at the Helmand border, Afghanistan. The conflict was between Afghan security forces and the Taliban. Since my teenage years, I had grown tired of hearing reports about suicide bombings in various places, including streets, schools, educational centers, mosques, wedding halls, and even hospitals. I was also exhausted from hearing about genocides of Hazaras and Sikhs in their own country. So, I didn’t take the news seriously either, but I never imagined that it would make my life so dark and painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later, suddenly, the Taliban took control of the first part of Helmand. This wasn’t very shocking, as they had done it before, and the security forces had been able to manage the situation multiple times. But unfortunately, over time, several provinces came under Taliban control, and the nightmare began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the night the Taliban took control of Mazar-e-Sharif. It was 11 p.m., and in the girls’ group, my classmates shared a picture of a Talib trying to raise the white flag of the Taliban government at the Shrine of Ali. Upon seeing that scene, all my hopes were utterly destroyed, and I fell into complete darkness. All I could think was: What if they force us to marry their soldiers? What if they attack our homes? What if they never let us study? Thousands of unanswered questions flooded my mind, and that night passed in a haze of anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, someone confused about their life tries to escape from reality. So, I did the same. I kept using social media to pass the time, but every video made me cry. Ten days passed in this cycle of crying and despair, and I promised myself not to think about the old Afghanistan. After about three months, I told myself I had to change. However, I had become depressed due to negative thoughts and hopelessness—my sleep, appetite, and entire life were falling apart. My mother and sister noticed, but they didn’t say anything to me. Sometimes I imagined myself as a machine that had been mistakenly filled with unnecessary materials or water, and from within, its parts were being destroyed, with smoke rising to the sky. I had no idea what to do. Seeing this state, I decided to fight. I started reading various books, mainly on psychology and fiction, and gradually, I got back into the habit of studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, my sister and I enrolled in English classes, and after a year, the university reopened its doors to girls. I completed my first semester (sixth semester)under Taliban rule, with the highest grades, although schools remained closed for girls. Gradually, hope returned to my heart. Initially, university classes were scheduled at different times for boys and girls, but due to poor management, this didn’t work well. Eventually, it was decided that boys and girls would attend classes on separate days. Two years passed like this, and I was in my ninth semester, which included practical studies. However, all educational centers were once again banned by the Taliban, especially for girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cope with the difficult situation and maintain my mental health, I joined a gym. But after only 10 days, the Taliban announced that women were no longer allowed to go to gyms or parks. I felt hopeless again and decided to learn something new. Although I had been doing lash extensions for about 5 years, I joined a tailoring class. Now, two years have passed, and I have learned tailoring. Recently, after two years finally they defended our final project with with online method and fortunately, I graduated with a high score in petroleum engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the changes in my country have transformed the lives of thousands of Afghan girls, including me. These experiences have taught me valuable lessons. I have learned patience, endured hardships, and grown stronger. Writing about these experiences hasn’t been easy for me due to the psychological effects of depression and stress. The human body focuses its energy on dealing with present challenges, which can sometimes harm memory, as the brain uses its resources to manage stressful situations and anxiety rather than store and retrieve past information. That’s why I can’t remember every detail clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I just want to say I will never give up. I am a warrior, the daughter of my homeland, and I will fight for the girls who are still deprived and for all of my dreams. I believe we will achieve our freedom soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At that time, every channel was broadcasting news about the war at the Helmand border, Afghanistan. The conflict was between Afghan security forces and the Taliban. Since my teenage years, I had grown tired of hearing reports about suicide bombings in various places, including streets, schools, educational centers, mosques, wedding halls, and even hospitals. I was also exhausted from hearing about genocides of Hazaras and Sikhs in their own country. So, I didn’t take the news seriously either, but I never imagined that it would make my life so dark and painful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl forced to marry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/22/marriage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl forced to marry" /><published>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/22/marriage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/22/marriage.html">&lt;p&gt;I always think to my self that maybe it was my fear of being judged that turned me into an introvert, because I am a girl, a woman. You can’t change how people treat you or what they say about you. All you can do is change how you react to it. Be the sun in other people’s lives, even if your own sky is cloudy. I always say to my friends that in the midst of endings, there are always new beginnings waiting to unfold. It is my slogan: Miracles happens when you choose to put yourself first and we must accept the end of something in order to begin something new. This story that I want to share with you is one of my friends whose family made her to get married with a boy that is 6 years older than her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Nov 6th that I heard the bad news..It was one of the worst day of my life. It was the time that I wanted to go to the school that teaches us secretly from the Taliban.  When I reached the school, my friends were too sad and worried. Everyone was present in the class that we expect Zahra. Zahra is a beautiful, kind and an intelligent girl. I asked her sister where is Zahra? She did not answer me. I got worried and sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 3:00 PM, when someone knocked on the door. I saw Zahra, there was waiting for me to open the door. Suddenly, she hugged me and started crying. I told her to wipe your beaudiful tears and come inside our house. After we settled down with tea, she wanted to talk with me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: Where were you my dear friend? You were not present in class today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: I have many problems these days. I am so alone Zainab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: What is the problem that makes you sad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: 2 days ago, one of our relatives came and wooed me for their boy. The boy is too old. You know I am so unlucky. I am not old enough to get married with a boy that is 5 or 6 years older than me. He is 20 or 21 but I am only 15. I do not know anything about married life. I want to continue my education and be the proud of my country and my people. I want to be a doctor to do many services for my country and my people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: But you are too young, you should not do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: Ah Zainab……I have no choice. My family are forcing me to marry him and say that I have to accept this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: It is impossible, what is the opinion of your father? Is he with you or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: I said that I am so unlucky. My father died 2 yeas ago. I do not have anyone to support me and save me from this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: What about your mother, brother or sister?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: It is their job. They do not want to hear my opinion. They do not listen to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: It is your life and you have to decide about your life. It is up to you, how to make your life and marry with who you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: hhhhh…..you know they behave like it is their life. If I say anything, my brother with slap me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: Why are they doing this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: you know the boy is so rich and they want me to marry him just for the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: oh my dear sister. You are faced with many problems! I can not do anything. If I could, I would. But unfortunately I can not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She cried a lot and said many bad words about her mother, brother and the father that left her with thousands of pains. She said look at the others - they are all getting ready for a great future but I am getting ready to bring up kids for my husband. On that day, we cried a lot and prayed to Allah for help. I heard today that her wedding will happen tomorrow night. She says goodbye to her future and her dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting go is not easy. It is painful. But one of the happiest moments in life is when you find the courage to let go of what you can not change. The sea does not need to prove its breadth. Do not let what you can not do get in the way of what you can do. Every great journey begins with a single step. Start now and let your determination fuel your path to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I promise that I will never give up and I will find for my freedom and save my future from darkness. I will never let anyone stand in the way of my goals and rights. It is not the end of my life. I continue continue continue on behalf of all unlucky girls in Afghanistan&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I always think to my self that maybe it was my fear of being judged that turned me into an introvert, because I am a girl, a woman. You can’t change how people treat you or what they say about you. All you can do is change how you react to it. Be the sun in other people’s lives, even if your own sky is cloudy. I always say to my friends that in the midst of endings, there are always new beginnings waiting to unfold. It is my slogan: Miracles happens when you choose to put yourself first and we must accept the end of something in order to begin something new. This story that I want to share with you is one of my friends whose family made her to get married with a boy that is 6 years older than her.</summary></entry></feed>