<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-08-16T22:24:02-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Silence of my Dreams</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">The girl at the checkpoint</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/04/checkpoint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl at the checkpoint" /><published>2024-08-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/04/checkpoint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/04/checkpoint.html">&lt;p&gt;characters:
M is a 23-year-old Afghan girl, eager to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R is a local Taliban commander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M approaches Commander R at the checkpoint near her university, which has recently been closed to girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Excuse me sir.  can I talk to you for a moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: (looks surprised) Yes, what is young lady?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: I noticed that all educational centers for girls are closed and I want to understand why we can’t continue our education.  I have only one semester left to reach my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: It is a new rule.  Girls should learn at home.  This is for your safety and to preserve our traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: But sir, my father taught me that science is light.  Without universities and professors, how can we see clearly in the dark?  If we are far from books and teachers, how can we learn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: Your father is wise, but there are different ways to acquire knowledge.  You can learn to cook, sew and manage the house.  This is respectable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Yes, but I wish to become a teacher.  I want to educate people with science and knowledge.  I want to help the children and youth of my country.  So that the light of knowledge is in their eyes.  Isn’t this also respectable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: (pauses, then speaks slowly) You speak with passion.  It’s rare and… it reminds me of my sister.  She had dreams like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: What happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: She was never able to pursue her dreams.  War… (his voice trails off) That’s why we make these laws to protect you from the hardships of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: I know the world is hard, but being deprived of education does not protect us.  It only makes us weaker against the struggles we have to face.  Isn’t it better to equip us with knowledge and power?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: (seems conflicted) You have a strong heart.  It is not common to hear such words from a young person of this age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Please reconsider allowing the University and School.  Not just for me, but for all the girls in my country.  Education will enlighten our ways and perhaps end this cycle of war and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: I will think about your words.  This is not my only decision, but I will talk to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Thank you sir.  That’s all we want - a chance to prove our worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: You should go home right now.  it’s getting late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Yes sir.  I have to go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">characters: M is a 23-year-old Afghan girl, eager to learn. R is a local Taliban commander.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl in exile</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/exile.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl in exile" /><published>2024-08-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/exile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/exile.html">&lt;p&gt;While the pains of my soul have deafened the ears of the sky, I cannot express my feelings correctly and accurately. I am the scarred body of my country’s history, which falls and rises on the endless road of life, moving towards an unknown end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am on the verge of my fourth year of collapse. In the summer of 2021, I lost everything and my life was practically destroyed. After spending some time under the conditions imposed by the Taliban, which cannot be called life, the invisible hand that encouraged me to continue forced me to choose between bad and worse. Therefore, I left the few things that were left in Afghanistan and took the path of emigration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been living as an immigrant for 18 months. Here life is grey and time passes slowly. I walk daily the length and width of my room, which is not more than 10 steps. I look at life in a daze and wonder what keeps me going. Is the one who pushes me forward, the same one who took everything from me and left me alone and helpless in the desert of life with a bag of suffering and misery? I still don’t know why this disaster happened to us, what sin should have such a terrible punishment? Or it was never like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I know for sure what I want life to be like. I have tasted freedom, love and hope. And I can definitely say that life for me lies in these three words. And l try to attain them and offer them to others. Maybe these are the salves for our wounds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">While the pains of my soul have deafened the ears of the sky, I cannot express my feelings correctly and accurately. I am the scarred body of my country’s history, which falls and rises on the endless road of life, moving towards an unknown end.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl in the school</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/02/TheSchool.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl in the school" /><published>2024-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/02/TheSchool</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/02/TheSchool.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you one of my experiences when I was student at course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course living under Taliban rules can make life dangerous and stressful. That was why we weren’t able to carry on studying. We have forced to beginning a secret class until get an official permission. Unhappily there was some individuals against knowledge who never want to accept that girls are the half of society and have right to studying. They have always wanted to expose everything and kill our mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, it was almost evening my classmates and I were busy to solving some mathematics questions and studying other subjects to become prepared for the test day. Suddenly my classmate comes in and said “Taliban came unannounced to check if there are girls in classes or not”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of us were shocked and scared, trying to work out how to escape from their sight. We hid behind the chairs. The only thing that I had in mind there was what is going to happen to us if they notice anything about the secrets class?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were quiet until the door has opened. I saw the manager who couldn’t stop laughing to us. He said “don’t worry they have came here for checking something else. It has nothing to do with you”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately we could breathe out again. I think the manager might said that words because of us that we feel convenience. But from then on our class has cancelled for about two months. Though the class gets started again. We hadn’t sufficient concentrate during the lectures and lost the excitement of studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently it was the day that I have never forgotten. My purpose of sharing this story is to make obvious that how the situation can be unacceptable and unfair for girls in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I want to share with you one of my experiences when I was student at course.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl in the market</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/01/TheMarket.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl in the market" /><published>2024-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/01/TheMarket</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/01/TheMarket.html">&lt;p&gt;It was August 2022, and a year had passed since the Taliban took over. After spending two weeks in Kabul for my brother’s wedding party, we came back to Mazar city. My sister and I went shopping, unaware that during these two weeks, the Taliban had implemented new rules for women, making it mandatory for them to wear the black hijab and mask, and restricting women from walking in the city. My sister had a mask and chador due to a cold, but I had chosen to adhere to the Islamic dress code that the Taliban had suggested before the new rules came in. While shopping, we were suddenly interrupted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Taliban are coming; be careful” someone shouted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shopkeeper gave me a strange look and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Leave my shop immediately and find a hiding place. I’ll sell you what you need when they’re gone. For now, leave this place!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was confused and asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why should we leave your shop?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that moment, someone from behind asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you a foreigner who just arrived in the country?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned around to see, a short Taliban member accompanied by four angry armed men questioning me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you Non-Muslim?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was confused and asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taliban angrily replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How can you be a Muslim? Why is your dress short, and why don’t you have a mask? Shameless girl, come with me to the Talib’s station…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was terrified and responded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s wrong with my dress? It’s not revealing or attractive. I didn’t know about wearing a mask; otherwise, I would have worn one!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Talib said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come with me to the Talib’s station. Who is your father? Your father is a non-believer who allows his daughter to leave the house like this. Call your father immediately to come here; otherwise, both of you stay here until he arrives!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of people had gathered around us. My sister remained silent from frustration, while I, as usual, responded with a sense of humor amidst fear. I called my father and explained the situation. Suddenly, a Taliban member demanded my phone and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll handle this!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took the phone from me and  removed the earphone, but the phone wasn’t working without it. He gave the phone back to me, frustrated with his inability to use it. I said to him:
“You need to use the earphone put the microphone closer to your mouth so your voice can be heard!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the Taliban were embarrassed, as he didn’t know how to use the earphone. I told him how to use the phone correctly, and he reluctantly complied. Meanwhile, the crowd of onlookers burst into laughter at the Taliban’s foolishness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Talib spoke with my father and continued to insult him. M father, who is indifferent to religion, argued with them and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My daughter has adhered to the Islamic dress code suggested by Islam; you have no right to criticize her!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taliban persisted in insulting him and, with the wrong address, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you want your daughters safe, come here so I will put you in the Talib’s station. We’re waiting for you. “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the second time, I realized the foolishness of the Taliban and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You gave the wrong address, tell him the right address so my father can find us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when all the people laughed, and each of the five were embarrassed and even angrier than before. Suddenly, they noticed a couple, a very well-dressed and modern man with a veiled and masked woman, who were passing by hand in hand, without noticing the scene. The short Talib immediately went up to them and in front of everyone, gave him a strong slap in his face. Everyone’s laughs turned to astonishment. The man asked angrily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why you did that, do you know who I am?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man was searching for his phone to call someone. The Talib grabbed the man’s phone and repeatedly gave him six slaps in his face and said to him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why are you so arrogant and well-dressed? Come with me to the Talib’s station, I’ll find out who you really are!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the man’s wife and family tearfully begged for his release, the Taliban showed no mercy. They forced him into their car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Taliban member then approached me and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get out of here, shameless girl, go home now; we’re waiting for your father!”
We immediately got into a taxi, keeping our distance from the Taliban. I called my father to prevent him from coming, and we safely returned home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were saddened and frightened when we arrived home, but my father comforted us, saying:
“These cursed ones will soon be gone from the country. Adhere to the exaggerated hijab for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the disappearance of these cursed individuals was just wishful thinking. Now, three years into the Taliban’s rule, conditions have changed for women. Over time universities, schools, workplaces, occasional recreational outings, sports salons, bathhouses… all are closed for women. Moreover they have mandates all for adhering to the hijab and mask, similar to the conditions of the COVID-19 quarantine. The Taliban are nothing more than coronavirus to Afghan women!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It was August 2022, and a year had passed since the Taliban took over. After spending two weeks in Kabul for my brother’s wedding party, we came back to Mazar city. My sister and I went shopping, unaware that during these two weeks, the Taliban had implemented new rules for women, making it mandatory for them to wear the black hijab and mask, and restricting women from walking in the city. My sister had a mask and chador due to a cold, but I had chosen to adhere to the Islamic dress code that the Taliban had suggested before the new rules came in. While shopping, we were suddenly interrupted:</summary></entry></feed>