<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-24T11:43:41-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chela Girl’s Empowerment Program</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">The girl confronted by the Taliban in Bamyan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/bitterness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl confronted by the Taliban in Bamyan" /><published>2025-01-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/bitterness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/bitterness.html">&lt;p&gt;The story I want to write is difficult for me, as it reflects the story of my life—a girl born in one of the worst times and under unfair conditions, a life full of bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bitterness stems from the fact that I had no influence or fault in choosing my circumstances, yet I am judged—harshly and unfairly—through the lens of gender and ethnicity. As a girl, I should have the most basic rights in life, but, unfortunately, I am denied even those. This harsh reality is so bitter and tragic for me that I drown in thought for hours. The bitterness of my story—and the stories of millions of other girls in every corner of this land—has grown even more bitter under the Taliban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was little, I heard the name “Taliban” on my father’s radio, which was always tuned to the BBC. The reporter always spoke about them with urgency. I didn’t understand what was being said, but I could tell from my father’s fixed gaze on the radio and his unbroken silence that it was nothing good. To me, the name “Taliban” held no meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me and my friends in that small village, our teammates and toys were more important than anything else. I never understood the truth about the Taliban because that truth was full of humiliation, stoning, executions, whipping, and forcing women and girls into the darkness of their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew older, like the suffering of the people around me, I came to realize that life was more than just toys. But I wish I hadn’t grown up. I wish I could have kept those toys, those happy friends, and the freedom to laugh out loud without judgment or wear what I wanted without fear of a veil. I learned, however, that life does not always follow human wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-15th-of-august&quot;&gt;The 15th of August&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 15th of August marked the beginning of a new era in the history of Afghanistan—a dark and regressive era in a history already full of twists and turns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this period, all the values and achievements we had struggled for—including women’s and girls’ rights, especially the right to education and work—were transformed into suffering. These rights had been gained through immense effort, challenges, and sacrifices. Terrorist attacks, targeted explosions in schools, mosques, and educational centers—particularly against the Hazara community—had plagued us, but we persevered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2021, I began working as a field vaccinator for COVID-19 in Bamyan province, one of the safest yet most deprived provinces over the past 26 years. It was a great opportunity to serve underprivileged people. However, it wasn’t long before we heard the sound of Taliban boots in the city. The tragic story of August 15th began, and everything changed overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our task was clear: My team of three—my coworker Sima, our driver, and I—was scheduled to visit the village of Qoli Haydar. On the way, we were surrounded by ten armed men on motorcycles, carrying white flags. They blocked our car, and fear gripped us as we shouted, “Why are the Taliban here?” I begged the driver, “Please don’t stop the car, just keep moving.” But the men surrounded us and demanded to know: “Where are you going? Who are you? What is your relationship with these girls?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driver, trembling with fear, answered, “They are COVID-19 vaccinators. We’re headed to Qoli Haydar village.” One of the men ordered, “Get out of the car!” The driver complied, while Sima and I remained inside. They ransacked the vehicle, taking everything, including the vaccine carrier and ice packs. One of them, puzzled by the ice packs, asked, “What are these?” The driver explained, “It’s frozen water for keeping the vaccines cold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the Taliban opened an ice pack, drank the water, and remarked, “Wow, cold water!” He shared it with the others, laughing, “Look at them, traveling with such luxuries as cold water.” I whispered to Sima, “If they drink the ice packs, the vaccines will be destroyed.” She begged me to stay silent, but I couldn’t. I stepped out and said in a hoarse voice, “This water is not drinkable; it’s for keeping the vaccines cold.” The men laughed loudly, mocking, “You eat or drink whatever you find!” and threw the ice packs to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another man sneered, “Shameless girls! How dare you work with men without a mahram? Thank God your corrupt government has fallen!” Panic boiled inside me, and dark thoughts swirled in my mind. I looked around, but there was nothing but the burning sun, towering mountains, and trees. Suddenly, one of them called the others away, saying, “Let’s go conquer the district. We’ll deal with these sparrows later.” They sped off on their motorcycles, and we breathed a sigh of relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hurriedly packed our things, got back in the car, and made our way to Qoli Haydar village. When we arrived, all the villagers had gathered in front of the mosque, their faces filled with fear and worry. After introducing ourselves, the village elder informed us, “The government has fallen. The Taliban have overtaken Kabul.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immediately said, “We should return to Jawqol because there’s no mobile network here, and I’m worried about my family in Kabul. I might never see them again.” But the villagers warned us, “The roads are too dangerous now; the Taliban may still be nearby.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite our fears, we managed to vaccinate 45 men and women. As time passed, my anxiety grew. I insisted, “We have to get back to Jawqol. My family will be worried about me.” When we finally reached the clinic, we discovered that all the employees had fled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father called me, and I told him, “I’m coming to Kabul.” But he replied, “Stay where you are. Don’t worry about us. The roads are too dangerous. When the situation improves, I’ll come to you.” Sima returned to her home, and I was left alone in the village. It was incredibly stressful—being a young woman without a mahram in an unfamiliar place. Yet, it was also an opportunity to connect with the women, girls, and people of the village on a deeper level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day, I struggled to comprehend the situation and repeatedly asked myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did the government go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did the commandos go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are the NATO forces and the United Nations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How was it possible for a group of men to emerge from the mountains and deserts and ruin the fate of millions in the blink of an eye? Unfortunately, there was no government, no men’s government, no United Nations, no human rights—only a dirty game in which everyone pursued their own interests. Women and girls were the primary victims of this political power play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the Taliban shattered my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The story I want to write is difficult for me, as it reflects the story of my life—a girl born in one of the worst times and under unfair conditions, a life full of bitterness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who refuses to hate her gender</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/23/gender.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who refuses to hate her gender" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/23/gender</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/23/gender.html">&lt;p&gt;I am a girl living in Afghanistan, having completed my bachelor’s degree in a society where women are often silenced, objectified, and forced to live with limitations. I’ve spent countless moments reflecting on the struggles we face, and the pain of it all has broken me at times. In my culture, especially in Asian countries like mine, when a man touches a woman’s body without consent, it’s not seen as shameful for him. But when she protests, she’s shamed. This injustice is a deep reflection of how little respect society has for a woman’s dignity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up, girls are told their only purpose is to marry, have children, and care for the family, while boys are encouraged to dream—to become leaders, scientists, businessmen. Women’s achievements are rarely celebrated. Where are the Afghan businesswomen, the scientists, the women who have succeeded on their own? Even globally, only a handful of women, like Marie Curie, have earned the Nobel Prize for their groundbreaking work. Why is that? Women have untapped potential, but society binds us with its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a time, during the oppressive Taliban era, when I questioned my worth as a woman. I hated my gender. I asked myself: Why must we bear so much pain—from excruciating periods to the struggles of childbirth and raising children? Even after giving birth, a woman can be blamed if she doesn’t produce a boy. The pain was overwhelming, and I started to lose faith. I wondered why there were no female messengers in religion and why men seemed to dominate history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then after joining education opportunity, I saw a new side of the world—a world full of kind, compassionate people. This shift in perspective changed my life. It made me realize that our worth isn’t tied to our pain or the constraints society places on us. We are defined by our strength, our resilience, and our ability to rise from the challenges we face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to think differently about God’s wisdom. If I could understand everything He has done, if I could think like Him, what would be the difference between us? Would I not be like God if I understood His every choice? Women are not accidents or lesser beings. We are strong, powerful creations with a purpose, and it is this strength that will shape the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all the women reading this: You are not alone. Your worth is immeasurable. No matter the struggles, your strength and courage define you. Know this—you are so much more than what society tries to make you believe. God created you strong, and it is in this strength that we find hope for a better world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am a girl living in Afghanistan, having completed my bachelor’s degree in a society where women are often silenced, objectified, and forced to live with limitations. I’ve spent countless moments reflecting on the struggles we face, and the pain of it all has broken me at times. In my culture, especially in Asian countries like mine, when a man touches a woman’s body without consent, it’s not seen as shameful for him. But when she protests, she’s shamed. This injustice is a deep reflection of how little respect society has for a woman’s dignity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl with a broken dream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/22/dreams.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl with a broken dream" /><published>2025-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/22/dreams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/22/dreams.html">&lt;p&gt;In the heart of darkness, when everything falls into silence, only the sound of silent dreams echoes in our ears. These dreams live in the heart of an Afghan girl; a girl who holds dreams and hopes in her heart. But in the real world, amidst the ruins of war and oppression, her dreams die one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an Afghan girl. A girl who sat in the classroom during the day and slept all night with big dreams. I wished to be useful to my country one day through my education. In my world, education was the only asylum for me. But the Taliban came and changed everything. I remember that one day in Seyed al-Shahda, there was an explosion and thousands of girls became martyrs. That day, it wasn’t only those girls who became martyrs; the souls of thousands of other girls were buried with them.Our house was near that school. I witnessed how  parents and families were broken, and how they died because of their pain. I also cried for them, for my country, for thousands of girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, when I went to school, I saw a blood-stained bag near to the mosque. I couldn’t control myself and cried. As I walked the half-hour distance to school, I kept crying. Perhaps thousands of other girls were being destroyed too. That day, the entire class was hopeless and upset. No one wanted  to study. I will never forget when our English teacher came in, greeted us, and then started teaching. But no one was wanted to study or even answer. When our teacher asked why, everyone said, “Why should we study? In the end, our fate will be the same as theirs. We will die too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But our teacher said something I have never forgotten. He said, “You should study for yourselves, and go abroad through scholarships or any other way. Don’t stay here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that moment, the only thing I thought about was my country and my people. I told the teacher, “If you and I are supposed to run away, then who will build this country? Who will serve it?” I responded. “You don’t want to go?” he asked me in disbelief. “No, why should I leave?” I replied seriously. If a million dollars is offered to you, would you still not leave?” He asked me again. But I stood with what I’ve said before “No.” This is my final answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gave me a puzzled look ,after awhile, he replied “You say this now, but one day, you will wish to leave. “Never!” I stated with certainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how wrong I was. I was a girl who never wanted to leave. Because I was not afraid of death, but I  was afraid of the destruction of my dreams. And that day, I said those words because I wanted to prove myself through knowledge and education and achieve my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a girl whose entire life and everything, even my belongings, was only knowledge. It was the only thing that was important  to me. I was so serious about my studying and school that I had even distanced myself from my childhood world. The day I first entered school, it took me years to realize that my father had passed away. Before that, I didn’t know and thought he was in Iran. But two days later, when I had just entered school, I found out that my father had died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a girl who had wished for seven or eight years to see her father just once, this news was harder than anything else. Some nights, I cried under the blanket, but I promised myself that one day, I would make my father proud. My father had brought us from the village to the city for education, and I promised that through education, I would make him proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Taliban took over Kabul, I was studying a history book. When I heard that the Taliban had taken the city, I closed the history book and said to myself, “finish.” And it truly finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, my mother became ill, and I went from being a girl who saw her  life in education to a girl who was only a nurse and caregiver for her mother. The situation had changed so much that I couldn’t even get close to my books. When my mother recovered and I returned to my books, everything had changed. Not only the situation, but I had changed as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taliban killed my dreams with their actions.Now, the only thing I want is to leave this country. See what the Taliban have done to this girl. What have they done to a girl who once had no desire to leave? My dreams and goals were all tied to this country and its government, but the Taliban took them from me by closing the doors of knowledge. Even if I go to the best country and study the best fields, I will never be the same girl again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dream was to study at Kabul University. To walk through the streets of Kabul and find a job. My dream was the happiness of my people and their smiles. But these dreams are dead. They were buried under the banner of the Taliban. Even if I leave one day, I will still not be the same girl. In reality, the Taliban killed a girl whose homeland was her life. They killed everything within me that was called “patriotism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I ask myself: “Where have I gone? What part of my life am I in now?” I was the girl whose everything was her country. Now, how can she leave it? Even if years pass, I will never find myself. The Taliban killed dreams that could have been realized in any country, except in their own. Even if I achieve my goals, my dreams are dead. Because in this country, no dream is fulfilled. This is the truth of the death of dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can no longer live as I once did. The Taliban, in fact, not only killed our bodies, but our souls and dreams as well. This pain is harder than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I still wonder if there will ever be a day when I can rebuild this country? Maybe not. Maybe I will just have to live with the memory of my dreams and remain loyal to them in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In the heart of darkness, when everything falls into silence, only the sound of silent dreams echoes in our ears. These dreams live in the heart of an Afghan girl; a girl who holds dreams and hopes in her heart. But in the real world, amidst the ruins of war and oppression, her dreams die one by one. I’m an Afghan girl. A girl who sat in the classroom during the day and slept all night with big dreams. I wished to be useful to my country one day through my education. In my world, education was the only asylum for me. But the Taliban came and changed everything. I remember that one day in Seyed al-Shahda, there was an explosion and thousands of girls became martyrs. That day, it wasn’t only those girls who became martyrs; the souls of thousands of other girls were buried with them.Our house was near that school. I witnessed how parents and families were broken, and how they died because of their pain. I also cried for them, for my country, for thousands of girls. The next morning, when I went to school, I saw a blood-stained bag near to the mosque. I couldn’t control myself and cried. As I walked the half-hour distance to school, I kept crying. Perhaps thousands of other girls were being destroyed too. That day, the entire class was hopeless and upset. No one wanted to study. I will never forget when our English teacher came in, greeted us, and then started teaching. But no one was wanted to study or even answer. When our teacher asked why, everyone said, “Why should we study? In the end, our fate will be the same as theirs. We will die too.” But our teacher said something I have never forgotten. He said, “You should study for yourselves, and go abroad through scholarships or any other way. Don’t stay here.” In that moment, the only thing I thought about was my country and my people. I told the teacher, “If you and I are supposed to run away, then who will build this country? Who will serve it?” I responded. “You don’t want to go?” he asked me in disbelief. “No, why should I leave?” I replied seriously. If a million dollars is offered to you, would you still not leave?” He asked me again. But I stood with what I’ve said before “No.” This is my final answer. He gave me a puzzled look ,after awhile, he replied “You say this now, but one day, you will wish to leave. “Never!” I stated with certainty.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who is a symbol for change</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/21/symbol.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who is a symbol for change" /><published>2025-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/21/symbol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/21/symbol.html">&lt;p&gt;The Courage of……..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A girl lived in a small village in Northern Afghanistan, surrounded by rugged hills and vast stretches of farmland. Her family was not wealthy, but they lived comfortably with enough food to eat and a small cozy home. She had always been a curious and bright child. She loved books and learning, often reading stories under the shade of a pomegranate tree near her house. But in her village, girls didn’t go to school. Education was considered unnecessary for girls, especially when there were other tasks to be done, like fetching water, cooking and helping with the farm. Her parents loved her deeply and wanted the best for her. But like many others in the village they believed that girls should prepared for marriage and family life, not education. However, her spirit could not be contained. She had big dreams that she wasn’t ready to give up on. Every time her younger brother went of to school her heart ached. She would watch him walk with his schoolbag, his face filled with excitement for the lessons ahead.  She would ask him about what he learned when he returned, and he would patiently tell her everything, even though she wasn’t able to attend school herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, after hearing another story about how a girl from a nearby village had become a teacher. She made a decision. She would learn, even if it meant breaking the rules of her village. She started by sneaking into her brother’s school in the afternoons, sitting quietly at the back of the classroom. Her brother didn’t know and neither did the teacher, but her thirst for knowledge grew every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first it was difficult. She was shy and nervous, worried about being discovered, but she had a fire inside her that kept her going. She learned how to read and write, starting with the letters of alphabet, then small words, and eventually reading entire stories. The teacher noticed her presence and rather than scolding her, he secretly encouraged her, giving her extra lessons in private after school. He admired her dedication, knowing that girls in the village were rarely given the chance to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One afternoon, her secret was discovered. Her parents were furious when they found out.  She had been attending school in secret. They didn’t understand why she would risk so much for something they thought was unnecessary. Her father, especially was upset.  “This is not our way” he said. “Girls belong at home not in school. You should be helping your mother, not wasting time with these books.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she didn’t give up. She stood firm and spoke from her heart. “Father, I want to learn because I want to help others. If I can learn, I can be a teacher. I can teach other girls like me who aren’t allowed to go to school. I want to make our village better to help people in a way no one else can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her words struck a chord with her mother, who, though hesitant, quietly supported her. After much discussion, her father, though reluctant, finally agreed to let her continue her studies. The condition was that she would attend school only during the evening hours, after the household chores were done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She worked hard, balancing her studies with the responsibilities at home. Over time, her dedication began to pay off. She became not just a student but a role model for other girls in the village. Slowly, the community began to see the value of education for girls, especially when the witnessed how her knowledge was making a real difference in their lives. She helped her neighbors learn how to read, write and manage the finances better. She shared health and hygiene lessons, and gradually, her efforts started to change the mindset of her village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year passed and she became the first girl in her village to attend high school. Eventually, she became a teacher, teaching not only in her own village but in surrounding communities as well.  Her students were both boys and girls, and she always made sure to encourage the girls in her classes to dream big and pursue education no matter the obstacles.  Her journey wasn’t easy but her perseverance, courage and belief in the power of education helped transform the lives of many. She became a symbol for change, not just in her village but in the broader region, inspiring many young girls to fight for their right to learn, to grow, and to live a life beyond the confines of traditional expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story represents the power of education and the courage to challenge societal norms. It highlights the importance of believing of one’s dreams and fighting for them even when faced with opposition. Like many young girls in Afghanistan and around the world, her determination can inspire others to pursue their goals despite the challenges they may face.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Courage of……..</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl who is a warrior</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/12/warrior.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl who is a warrior" /><published>2025-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/12/warrior</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/12/warrior.html">&lt;p&gt;At that time, every channel was broadcasting news about the war at the Helmand border, Afghanistan. The conflict was between Afghan security forces and the Taliban. Since my teenage years, I had grown tired of hearing reports about suicide bombings in various places, including streets, schools, educational centers, mosques, wedding halls, and even hospitals. I was also exhausted from hearing about genocides of Hazaras and Sikhs in their own country. So, I didn’t take the news seriously either, but I never imagined that it would make my life so dark and painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later, suddenly, the Taliban took control of the first part of Helmand. This wasn’t very shocking, as they had done it before, and the security forces had been able to manage the situation multiple times. But unfortunately, over time, several provinces came under Taliban control, and the nightmare began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the night the Taliban took control of Mazar-e-Sharif. It was 11 p.m., and in the girls’ group, my classmates shared a picture of a Talib trying to raise the white flag of the Taliban government at the Shrine of Ali. Upon seeing that scene, all my hopes were utterly destroyed, and I fell into complete darkness. All I could think was: What if they force us to marry their soldiers? What if they attack our homes? What if they never let us study? Thousands of unanswered questions flooded my mind, and that night passed in a haze of anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, someone confused about their life tries to escape from reality. So, I did the same. I kept using social media to pass the time, but every video made me cry. Ten days passed in this cycle of crying and despair, and I promised myself not to think about the old Afghanistan. After about three months, I told myself I had to change. However, I had become depressed due to negative thoughts and hopelessness—my sleep, appetite, and entire life were falling apart. My mother and sister noticed, but they didn’t say anything to me. Sometimes I imagined myself as a machine that had been mistakenly filled with unnecessary materials or water, and from within, its parts were being destroyed, with smoke rising to the sky. I had no idea what to do. Seeing this state, I decided to fight. I started reading various books, mainly on psychology and fiction, and gradually, I got back into the habit of studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, my sister and I enrolled in English classes, and after a year, the university reopened its doors to girls. I completed my first semester (sixth semester)under Taliban rule, with the highest grades, although schools remained closed for girls. Gradually, hope returned to my heart. Initially, university classes were scheduled at different times for boys and girls, but due to poor management, this didn’t work well. Eventually, it was decided that boys and girls would attend classes on separate days. Two years passed like this, and I was in my ninth semester, which included practical studies. However, all educational centers were once again banned by the Taliban, especially for girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cope with the difficult situation and maintain my mental health, I joined a gym. But after only 10 days, the Taliban announced that women were no longer allowed to go to gyms or parks. I felt hopeless again and decided to learn something new. Although I had been doing lash extensions for about 5 years, I joined a tailoring class. Now, two years have passed, and I have learned tailoring. Recently, after two years finally they defended our final project with with online method and fortunately, I graduated with a high score in petroleum engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the changes in my country have transformed the lives of thousands of Afghan girls, including me. These experiences have taught me valuable lessons. I have learned patience, endured hardships, and grown stronger. Writing about these experiences hasn’t been easy for me due to the psychological effects of depression and stress. The human body focuses its energy on dealing with present challenges, which can sometimes harm memory, as the brain uses its resources to manage stressful situations and anxiety rather than store and retrieve past information. That’s why I can’t remember every detail clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I just want to say I will never give up. I am a warrior, the daughter of my homeland, and I will fight for the girls who are still deprived and for all of my dreams. I believe we will achieve our freedom soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At that time, every channel was broadcasting news about the war at the Helmand border, Afghanistan. The conflict was between Afghan security forces and the Taliban. Since my teenage years, I had grown tired of hearing reports about suicide bombings in various places, including streets, schools, educational centers, mosques, wedding halls, and even hospitals. I was also exhausted from hearing about genocides of Hazaras and Sikhs in their own country. So, I didn’t take the news seriously either, but I never imagined that it would make my life so dark and painful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl forced to marry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/22/marriage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl forced to marry" /><published>2024-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/22/marriage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/22/marriage.html">&lt;p&gt;I always think to my self that maybe it was my fear of being judged that turned me into an introvert, because I am a girl, a woman. You can’t change how people treat you or what they say about you. All you can do is change how you react to it. Be the sun in other people’s lives, even if your own sky is cloudy. I always say to my friends that in the midst of endings, there are always new beginnings waiting to unfold. It is my slogan: Miracles happens when you choose to put yourself first and we must accept the end of something in order to begin something new. This story that I want to share with you is one of my friends whose family made her to get married with a boy that is 6 years older than her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Nov 6th that I heard the bad news..It was one of the worst day of my life. It was the time that I wanted to go to the school that teaches us secretly from the Taliban.  When I reached the school, my friends were too sad and worried. Everyone was present in the class that we expect Zahra. Zahra is a beautiful, kind and an intelligent girl. I asked her sister where is Zahra? She did not answer me. I got worried and sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 3:00 PM, when someone knocked on the door. I saw Zahra, there was waiting for me to open the door. Suddenly, she hugged me and started crying. I told her to wipe your beaudiful tears and come inside our house. After we settled down with tea, she wanted to talk with me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: Where were you my dear friend? You were not present in class today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: I have many problems these days. I am so alone Zainab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: What is the problem that makes you sad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: 2 days ago, one of our relatives came and wooed me for their boy. The boy is too old. You know I am so unlucky. I am not old enough to get married with a boy that is 5 or 6 years older than me. He is 20 or 21 but I am only 15. I do not know anything about married life. I want to continue my education and be the proud of my country and my people. I want to be a doctor to do many services for my country and my people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: But you are too young, you should not do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: Ah Zainab……I have no choice. My family are forcing me to marry him and say that I have to accept this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: It is impossible, what is the opinion of your father? Is he with you or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: I said that I am so unlucky. My father died 2 yeas ago. I do not have anyone to support me and save me from this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: What about your mother, brother or sister?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: It is their job. They do not want to hear my opinion. They do not listen to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: It is your life and you have to decide about your life. It is up to you, how to make your life and marry with who you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: hhhhh…..you know they behave like it is their life. If I say anything, my brother with slap me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: Why are they doing this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahra: you know the boy is so rich and they want me to marry him just for the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zainab: oh my dear sister. You are faced with many problems! I can not do anything. If I could, I would. But unfortunately I can not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She cried a lot and said many bad words about her mother, brother and the father that left her with thousands of pains. She said look at the others - they are all getting ready for a great future but I am getting ready to bring up kids for my husband. On that day, we cried a lot and prayed to Allah for help. I heard today that her wedding will happen tomorrow night. She says goodbye to her future and her dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting go is not easy. It is painful. But one of the happiest moments in life is when you find the courage to let go of what you can not change. The sea does not need to prove its breadth. Do not let what you can not do get in the way of what you can do. Every great journey begins with a single step. Start now and let your determination fuel your path to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I promise that I will never give up and I will find for my freedom and save my future from darkness. I will never let anyone stand in the way of my goals and rights. It is not the end of my life. I continue continue continue on behalf of all unlucky girls in Afghanistan&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I always think to my self that maybe it was my fear of being judged that turned me into an introvert, because I am a girl, a woman. You can’t change how people treat you or what they say about you. All you can do is change how you react to it. Be the sun in other people’s lives, even if your own sky is cloudy. I always say to my friends that in the midst of endings, there are always new beginnings waiting to unfold. It is my slogan: Miracles happens when you choose to put yourself first and we must accept the end of something in order to begin something new. This story that I want to share with you is one of my friends whose family made her to get married with a boy that is 6 years older than her.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl at the checkpoint</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/04/checkpoint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl at the checkpoint" /><published>2024-08-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/04/checkpoint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/04/checkpoint.html">&lt;p&gt;characters:
M is a 23-year-old Afghan girl, eager to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R is a local Taliban commander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M approaches Commander R at the checkpoint near her university, which has recently been closed to girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Excuse me sir.  can I talk to you for a moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: (looks surprised) Yes, what is young lady?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: I noticed that all educational centers for girls are closed and I want to understand why we can’t continue our education.  I have only one semester left to reach my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: It is a new rule.  Girls should learn at home.  This is for your safety and to preserve our traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: But sir, my father taught me that science is light.  Without universities and professors, how can we see clearly in the dark?  If we are far from books and teachers, how can we learn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: Your father is wise, but there are different ways to acquire knowledge.  You can learn to cook, sew and manage the house.  This is respectable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Yes, but I wish to become a teacher.  I want to educate people with science and knowledge.  I want to help the children and youth of my country.  So that the light of knowledge is in their eyes.  Isn’t this also respectable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: (pauses, then speaks slowly) You speak with passion.  It’s rare and… it reminds me of my sister.  She had dreams like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: What happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: She was never able to pursue her dreams.  War… (his voice trails off) That’s why we make these laws to protect you from the hardships of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: I know the world is hard, but being deprived of education does not protect us.  It only makes us weaker against the struggles we have to face.  Isn’t it better to equip us with knowledge and power?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: (seems conflicted) You have a strong heart.  It is not common to hear such words from a young person of this age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Please reconsider allowing the University and School.  Not just for me, but for all the girls in my country.  Education will enlighten our ways and perhaps end this cycle of war and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: I will think about your words.  This is not my only decision, but I will talk to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Thank you sir.  That’s all we want - a chance to prove our worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R: You should go home right now.  it’s getting late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M: Yes sir.  I have to go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">characters: M is a 23-year-old Afghan girl, eager to learn. R is a local Taliban commander.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl in exile</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/exile.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl in exile" /><published>2024-08-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/exile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/exile.html">&lt;p&gt;While the pains of my soul have deafened the ears of the sky, I cannot express my feelings correctly and accurately. I am the scarred body of my country’s history, which falls and rises on the endless road of life, moving towards an unknown end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am on the verge of my fourth year of collapse. In the summer of 2021, I lost everything and my life was practically destroyed. After spending some time under the conditions imposed by the Taliban, which cannot be called life, the invisible hand that encouraged me to continue forced me to choose between bad and worse. Therefore, I left the few things that were left in Afghanistan and took the path of emigration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been living as an immigrant for 18 months. Here life is grey and time passes slowly. I walk daily the length and width of my room, which is not more than 10 steps. I look at life in a daze and wonder what keeps me going. Is the one who pushes me forward, the same one who took everything from me and left me alone and helpless in the desert of life with a bag of suffering and misery? I still don’t know why this disaster happened to us, what sin should have such a terrible punishment? Or it was never like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I know for sure what I want life to be like. I have tasted freedom, love and hope. And I can definitely say that life for me lies in these three words. And l try to attain them and offer them to others. Maybe these are the salves for our wounds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">While the pains of my soul have deafened the ears of the sky, I cannot express my feelings correctly and accurately. I am the scarred body of my country’s history, which falls and rises on the endless road of life, moving towards an unknown end.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl in the school</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/02/TheSchool.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl in the school" /><published>2024-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/02/TheSchool</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/02/TheSchool.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you one of my experiences when I was student at course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course living under Taliban rules can make life dangerous and stressful. That was why we weren’t able to carry on studying. We have forced to beginning a secret class until get an official permission. Unhappily there was some individuals against knowledge who never want to accept that girls are the half of society and have right to studying. They have always wanted to expose everything and kill our mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, it was almost evening my classmates and I were busy to solving some mathematics questions and studying other subjects to become prepared for the test day. Suddenly my classmate comes in and said “Taliban came unannounced to check if there are girls in classes or not”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of us were shocked and scared, trying to work out how to escape from their sight. We hid behind the chairs. The only thing that I had in mind there was what is going to happen to us if they notice anything about the secrets class?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were quiet until the door has opened. I saw the manager who couldn’t stop laughing to us. He said “don’t worry they have came here for checking something else. It has nothing to do with you”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately we could breathe out again. I think the manager might said that words because of us that we feel convenience. But from then on our class has cancelled for about two months. Though the class gets started again. We hadn’t sufficient concentrate during the lectures and lost the excitement of studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently it was the day that I have never forgotten. My purpose of sharing this story is to make obvious that how the situation can be unacceptable and unfair for girls in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I want to share with you one of my experiences when I was student at course.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The girl in the market</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/01/TheMarket.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The girl in the market" /><published>2024-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/01/TheMarket</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/01/TheMarket.html">&lt;p&gt;It was August 2022, and a year had passed since the Taliban took over. After spending two weeks in Kabul for my brother’s wedding party, we came back to Mazar city. My sister and I went shopping, unaware that during these two weeks, the Taliban had implemented new rules for women, making it mandatory for them to wear the black hijab and mask, and restricting women from walking in the city. My sister had a mask and chador due to a cold, but I had chosen to adhere to the Islamic dress code that the Taliban had suggested before the new rules came in. While shopping, we were suddenly interrupted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Taliban are coming; be careful” someone shouted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shopkeeper gave me a strange look and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Leave my shop immediately and find a hiding place. I’ll sell you what you need when they’re gone. For now, leave this place!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was confused and asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why should we leave your shop?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that moment, someone from behind asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you a foreigner who just arrived in the country?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned around to see, a short Taliban member accompanied by four angry armed men questioning me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you Non-Muslim?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was confused and asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taliban angrily replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How can you be a Muslim? Why is your dress short, and why don’t you have a mask? Shameless girl, come with me to the Talib’s station…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was terrified and responded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s wrong with my dress? It’s not revealing or attractive. I didn’t know about wearing a mask; otherwise, I would have worn one!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Talib said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come with me to the Talib’s station. Who is your father? Your father is a non-believer who allows his daughter to leave the house like this. Call your father immediately to come here; otherwise, both of you stay here until he arrives!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of people had gathered around us. My sister remained silent from frustration, while I, as usual, responded with a sense of humor amidst fear. I called my father and explained the situation. Suddenly, a Taliban member demanded my phone and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll handle this!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took the phone from me and  removed the earphone, but the phone wasn’t working without it. He gave the phone back to me, frustrated with his inability to use it. I said to him:
“You need to use the earphone put the microphone closer to your mouth so your voice can be heard!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the Taliban were embarrassed, as he didn’t know how to use the earphone. I told him how to use the phone correctly, and he reluctantly complied. Meanwhile, the crowd of onlookers burst into laughter at the Taliban’s foolishness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Talib spoke with my father and continued to insult him. M father, who is indifferent to religion, argued with them and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My daughter has adhered to the Islamic dress code suggested by Islam; you have no right to criticize her!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taliban persisted in insulting him and, with the wrong address, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you want your daughters safe, come here so I will put you in the Talib’s station. We’re waiting for you. “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the second time, I realized the foolishness of the Taliban and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You gave the wrong address, tell him the right address so my father can find us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when all the people laughed, and each of the five were embarrassed and even angrier than before. Suddenly, they noticed a couple, a very well-dressed and modern man with a veiled and masked woman, who were passing by hand in hand, without noticing the scene. The short Talib immediately went up to them and in front of everyone, gave him a strong slap in his face. Everyone’s laughs turned to astonishment. The man asked angrily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why you did that, do you know who I am?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man was searching for his phone to call someone. The Talib grabbed the man’s phone and repeatedly gave him six slaps in his face and said to him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why are you so arrogant and well-dressed? Come with me to the Talib’s station, I’ll find out who you really are!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the man’s wife and family tearfully begged for his release, the Taliban showed no mercy. They forced him into their car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Taliban member then approached me and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get out of here, shameless girl, go home now; we’re waiting for your father!”
We immediately got into a taxi, keeping our distance from the Taliban. I called my father to prevent him from coming, and we safely returned home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were saddened and frightened when we arrived home, but my father comforted us, saying:
“These cursed ones will soon be gone from the country. Adhere to the exaggerated hijab for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the disappearance of these cursed individuals was just wishful thinking. Now, three years into the Taliban’s rule, conditions have changed for women. Over time universities, schools, workplaces, occasional recreational outings, sports salons, bathhouses… all are closed for women. Moreover they have mandates all for adhering to the hijab and mask, similar to the conditions of the COVID-19 quarantine. The Taliban are nothing more than coronavirus to Afghan women!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It was August 2022, and a year had passed since the Taliban took over. After spending two weeks in Kabul for my brother’s wedding party, we came back to Mazar city. My sister and I went shopping, unaware that during these two weeks, the Taliban had implemented new rules for women, making it mandatory for them to wear the black hijab and mask, and restricting women from walking in the city. My sister had a mask and chador due to a cold, but I had chosen to adhere to the Islamic dress code that the Taliban had suggested before the new rules came in. While shopping, we were suddenly interrupted:</summary></entry></feed>